Gowtham Vijayaragavan

Pleasanton, CA • Phone: 925-520-5740 • E-Mail: gowthyj@gmail.com

Summary

In my 4 years of experience as a software engineer, I have worked across all levels of the development stack. I am passionate in building applications that are not only beautiful, but also fully accessible, performant, and ensured to be the highest quality through automation.

Skills

- Proficient: Java, Javascript, Html5, CSS, Sass, Git, Selenium, Bash
- Paradigms/Methodologies: Test Driven Development, REST, Responsive Design, Accessibility, Graceful Degredation, Progressive Enhancement, Unit Testing, Integration Testing, Performance Testing

Experience

Full-Stack Software Engineer, Real Time Collaboration at Salesforce November 2016 - Present

- Developed integrations for partners' web collaboration tools, on both frontend (Aura JS Framework) and backend (Java, Spring).
- Spiked Web-Ex integration, collaborating with both internal and external teams to assess technical dependencies and determine work required. Developed whole front-end for feature.
- In parallel with feature development, tracked performance using command-line scripts (Bash) to automate pulling data from Splunk
 and uploaded to internal data visualization framework.

Frontend Software Engineer, Web Frameworks at Workday June 2015 - October 2016

- Developed several customer-facing features for main Workday application, using in-house framework built on top of GWT
- Updated responsiveness and fixed behavior of numerous components
- Collaborated with UX designers to optimize usability and aesthetics of application
- Improved Accessibility of External Career Site and main application by adding keyboard navigability to components and updating
 them to better follow WAI-ARIA specifications. Used Jaws as benchmark for screen readability.

Software Engineer, Test Frameworks at Workday

August 2013 - June 2015

- Maintained test automation framework used across all functional automation teams and UI team.
- Developed automation components as respective UI components were made, collaborating closely with both UI developers and functional automators.
- Documented framework and reinforced best practices with automators, to ensure codebase was clean, modular, and reusable.

University Research/Internships

- Research Assistant, UC Davis Graduate School of Management (July December 2012)
- Data Management Assistant, Center for Transnational Health (April September 2012

Education

UC Davis

September 2009 - June 2013

Computer Science and Engineering Major, with a minor in Technology Management